hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah kurkowski and on this podcast I
talk about ways for you to grow your
life grow your business make more money
if you're a coach trainer a thought
leader somebody with a message that
wants to impact people my mission is to
create multi-million dollar coaches
trainers authors and thought leaders and
to help people take what's inside their
brain
put it out there reach as many people as
possible and make a whole heck of a ton
of money doing so and so welcome to this
podcast the grow Your Life podcast I've
been doing this for a long time the
episodes are incredible best way to
listen through the podcast don't go in
order number order pick the topics that
resonate with you that you feel like you
need help with and today we're going to
be talking about pivoting the topic of
your niche of your offer of your opt-in
offer your paid offer
adjusting the topic
to be more profitable for you and one of
my favorite books that really kind of
helped me resonate with this and an
example that I'm going to give you of
this of how we've applied this in our
businesses over the years you know my
background for those of you that I
haven't met yet I've built multiple
eight-figure mentorship and coaching
businesses I've been in the industry for
two decades
and I help people create multi-million
dollar mentorship businesses that's what
we show people how to do from scratch
start from zero and get to that Millions
level not just dabbling but actually
impacting millions of lives around the
world and and our clients have impacted
millions of lives we've impacted
millions of lives by doing this
but even if you're just getting started
and this message is for those of you
that are getting started you know if
you're under the ten thousand twenty
thousand dollar a month a month Mark in
your business this is going to be a
great message for you or if you've
plateaued maybe you hit forty to sixty
thousand or a hundred thousand
you know above a hundred thousand
dollars a month I mean that's 1.5
million dollars a year
um the way to get unstuck is going to be
with systems with hiring a team and
really automating a lot of your efforts
instead of you having to show up and do
them your team and your system does
everything for you uh below the ten
thousand dollar Mark that's what we're
going to talk about is the topic that
you're actually mentoring on here's an
example of this that we used you know we
worked with a client his name was Rick
Pino and we helped him with his worship
coach program and he had some success
with some different ideas and topics but
the average month you know initially was
doing about ten to twenty thousand
dollars a month I mean that was really
good because he he already had an
audience people that loved him that
followed him so it was an instant
multi-six figure income for him which
was great that's not necessarily the
case of people that don't have an email
list but he couldn't seem to break past
that level until we pivoted the language
of who we were reaching and breaking
past the just ten thousand dollar a
month level we pivoted to not just all
worshipers because that's what he had a
heart for and his message was for
everybody who who was basically a
Christian that loved Jesus as a it was
like a wide-ranging message that like
you anybody who loves God could hear it
and would get fired up by it like it was
good stuff and and I've and I've
listened to him teach this before and
I'm not the Target customer of his
mentorship program but I've enjoyed his
preaching and teaching and so so his
message was like wide-ranging reached a
lot of people but we had to Pivot down
to
the group of people that was most likely
because here's what happened we couldn't
seem to get new people to join us okay
we could hit that 10 to 20 000 a month a
month mark But new people weren't
actually coming into the ecosystem new
people weren't actually jumping in with
us and so it was like okay this is dying
this isn't working we had to move over
here to the level of worship songwriters
who had struggled to get their music out
there and heard okay so that was a
wide-ranging pivot from just you know
all Christians to those that have
written and published music but that
produced a business that was making a
million dollars per month
by pivoting in the direction of what was
most profitable that had the most buyers
in it and so that's what we want to look
at is we want to Pivot in that direction
Alex hermosi's book 100 million dollar
offers talks about this that the
difference between a business that's
just barely trying to get by and one
that's thriving is having an audience of
people that has money to actually spend
with you that you're actually marketing
and selling a product or service to
people that actually have finances for
what you're offering and so if you find
yourself constantly talking to people
that don't have finances that's one of
the first things that you want to do is
you want to Pivot in the direction of
those that do have finances so then you
can actually fund the whole thing at
that point you might say yeah but my
message can help so and so and I just I
have a heart for these people listen
that's great keep doing that
but build your business around what's
most profitable take the profits because
they're going to be exponential I'm
talking the difference between five to
ten thousand dollars that's dabbling you
might say that's a good money for you
but that to a million dollars a month I
mean that the that's a dramatic shift
over here
and so the amount of impact that then
can be brought back over to this group
of people was exponentially greater than
just staying in the small tiny Cocoon of
what's safe and what you know and what
your heart's desire is okay and so we
found the exact same thing uh with my
mom's business
with um with with this business in in my
own business you know when I started I
started helping people anybody who
wanted to use Facebook ads in a website
I would show you how to get on the
internet and make money online
anybody can make money online I mean I I
stand behind that I stand behind that
statement today
um but
I couldn't get just anybody to become a
paid customer of mine and and I was even
getting some complaints from certain
groups of people that quite frankly I
didn't have experience
helping that niche of online marketing
you know e-commerce and agencies uh but
I
realize that the people that were
getting the most results that were
testimonies and my 20-year track record
of building eight-figure mentorship
businesses
was mentors coaches trainers authors and
thought leaders
that want to create these mentorship
models a personal brand online and make
millions of dollars and so what I found
is the people that actually had that
trajectory they were always buying from
me and they would give me positive
reviews and our experience together was
just
fun
versus trying to pull teeth with the
other group of people
so even though I could help all these
people and they were coming to me for
help I had to Pivot in the direction of
those that were most profitable in our
business within a year of doing that
over over a million dollars in this
business right here okay
I built multiple eight-figure mentorship
businesses and we started this one the
our mentorship program just one year ago
and and since then our business has made
over a million dollars and so the pivot
is in the direction of figuring out who
is most likely to spend a lot of money
with you
who is most likely to buy from you
that also has the problem that you can
solve
and so not being so generic with trying
to help everybody gain confidence or or
improve their health focusing in on
maybe Executives or people starting a
business of some kind focus in on a
group of people that has an Expendable
income and they're willing to solve the
problem now the other thing is is that
sometimes our offers perceived value is
misaligned with people because of how
we're explaining it we can over explain
what our offer is and the the right
people who it's meant for will actually
turn it down because they're overwhelmed
and confused by what you actually do
with them so getting Clarity in how you
express and explain it is important and
the final thing that I say is we want to
keep our ear to the ground the most
important thing is the feedback loop
keep your ear to the ground listening to
the marketplace what do they want what
are they telling you that they want
what are they explaining to you that
they want to learn
specifically
by working with you like like not what
you want to teach them that's a
difference
but what are they actually saying hey
I have a problem in this area I need to
grow in this area
and it may be related to something that
you don't even want to talk about we
found this with Rick Pino as well
you know one of the topics that was the
most profitable for him was an offer
that said become a world famous worship
leader and
in conversations with with Rick
the idea of helping people become a
world famous worship leader was
nauseating to him it was so outside of
the realm of what he felt comfortable
with
but that right there was what people
actually wanted
and so he was able to then deliver
by finding songwriters that wanted to
become world famous and selling them on
the dream of becoming world famous which
he had a track record of doing
um so what do you have a track record of
and you might say well I've never helped
anybody become famous in music that's so
big or I've never helped anybody become
a millionaire that's so big
but you have helped people or you have
done something
that people don't know how to do that
they're struggling to do that they that
they want to learn how to do you can
also learn a new topic as well my mom
did this you know three years ago my mom
she was building a multi-million dollar
mentorship business she didn't have a
lot of experience at all in trading
stocks
none
three years ago and she did the very
thing that that you can do as well is
she learned a new skill set and then
mentored people that were just a little
bit further behind where she was on that
and has a multi-million dollar stocks
mentorship group
and so you don't have to have 20 years
of experience you could have six months
or 12 months of experience and then
start working with people and mentoring
them now by the way that's also uh poo
pooed in the industry it's it's um it's
looked down upon to do that I'm one of
the few people that encourages it and I
think that that that we have we there is
no reason that you have to wait until
you reach some certain level of success
until you are good enough to go put out
there a mentorship business and I get
that you may not like that I'm saying
that
but I'm going to continue to keep saying
it because I want to keep inspiring
people that are beginners and and
advanced and experts alike okay
it's one of the biggest areas why a lot
of
experts actually
don't work with me because
uh they they they they don't like that
I'm empowering the beginner so much and
and so that's why I try to empower
people at all different levels to help
them because I know that I know that I
know that this is an opportunity and and
and and and that there's so many people
out there with a great message in their
heart and something that they want to
share with people and something that
they want to put out there but they've
had people tell them that they're not
good enough yet or they're not ready yet
and that they've held back on those
things and those topics that could be
profitable for them in a business
because some person told them that they
needed to get some sort of Accolade or
certification or something in order
before they were they had the right and
permission to be able to get clients in
that Niche and I'm and I'm here to tell
you that's just simply not true at all
um none of this business thank God right
now is regulated
um there's no regulations around any of
that so that that's part of that's one
of the reasons why there's a lot of
scammers out there there are there are
absolutely scammers out there people
that are selling a dream can't deliver
on it but I would think that if you're
somebody who's listening to me right now
and who we attract in our business that
you're somebody with integrity
and and and and that you're somebody who
is helping people
and so
I would encourage you to not be afraid
of this
putting something out there that maybe
you're a newbie at or you're just
learning pivoting in the direction of
maybe you've got skill set over here now
people aren't really buying it over here
but you also have some skill set over
here and you can grow in that skill set
as you're doing it
you know I rick wasn't the best at
marketing or at at even getting his
music out there but he was able to build
a business around that because he was
also getting better at it over time
while working with these clients and
people
and so I I see way too many people
holding back from what could be their
multi-million dollar pivot because they
think that they're not ready yet
and they think it's it's tied and
attached to their their integrity don't
let the fear
of people judging you
of
you not being good enough of am I going
to disappoint people
we talked about that last week in the
podcast the power of disappointing
people don't let any of those things the
opinions of other people stop you from
putting your business out there and even
moving in that direction that is most
profitable for you you will have more
impact overall the people that were
meant to work with you that were going
to come into your space anyways
you're not going to be losing clients by
doing this I hear people say I'm going
to lose clients by doing this you're not
going to because they were never going
to pay you anyways as a client and so
you have this hopeful expectation that
they might show up or change their mind
and they're really not going to because
the people that are actually going to
pay you money as you have
made a boundary and drawn the line and
said this is how much I need to be paid
for my mentorship
we need to make a decision that we're
worth charging what we're Worth to
people
and not let anybody erode that or
undermine that or and I'm not talking
about doing that in a in a jerk off
type of a way either
I'm talking about you know who you are
that you don't worry about what other
people's opinions are of you you know
there's a story from Alex hermosi that
there's this old white man on YouTube
and there were hecklers underneath the
post calling him a fake Guru and a scam
artist and that he knew nothing about
finances and and and the guy that they
were heckling was
a man named Ray dalio who is worth over
20 billion dollars and so it shows that
even at his level if you can't avoid the
haters or the hecklers or things like
that and you're not going to please
everybody that there's no reason why we
should expect it even at the beginning
level and so realize that you're going
to have negativity come your way when
you put yourself out there there's no
way of avoiding it
you just have to strengthen your skin
internally your inner fortitude needs to
become stronger against the mudslinging
that will happen as you start to put
yourself out there okay and so we can't
let the fear of what other people think
about us or imposter syndrome get so
caught up in our thoughts and in our
day-to-day life that we make our
decisions in business based off of
trying to make people approve of us
trying to make people agree with us
trying to make people see our side just
do what you know how to do even if
nobody agrees with you and stay on the
path that you know is going to produce
the results you want
and that's what I gotta say and anything
that comes in your mind that causes you
to question this or makes you think that
this is wrong or bad
I would question that and challenge that
thinking as to why
your thoughts are trying to keep you in
a restrained box of small thinking
and step out and take action
and create something bigger than maybe
what you've previously imagined before
all right so that's what this podcast
has been that's what our client growth
accelerator is all about that's what our
events are about and that's what I'm
excited to help you with as well if
you're in my ecosystem you're able to
create millions of dollars in a
mentorship business and I'm here to help
you every step of the way we'll talk
soon have a good one
[Music]
thank you